[
  {
    "question": "Who invented OOP?",
    "answer": "Alan Kay",
    "option1": "Adele Goldberg",
    "option2": "Andrea Ferro",
    "option3": "Dennis Ritchie"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is not a feature of OOP in general definitions?",
    "answer": "Duplicate/Redundant data",
    "option1": "Efficient Code",
    "option2": "Code reusability",
    "option3": "Modularity"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which was the first purely object oriented programming language developed?",
    "answer": "SmallTalk",
    "option1": "Kotlin",
    "option2": "Java",
    "option3": "C++"
  },
  {
    "question": "When OOP concept did first came into picture?",
    "answer": "1970’s",
    "option1": "1980’s",
    "option2": "1995",
    "option3": "1993"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which feature of OOP indicates code reusability?",
    "answer": "Inheritance",
    "option1": "Polymorphism.h",
    "option2": "Abstraction",
    "option3": "Encapsulation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which header file is required in C++ to use OOP?",
    "answer": "OOP can be used without using any header file",
    "option1": "stdlib.h",
    "option2": "iostream.h",
    "option3": "stdio.h"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why Java is Partially OOP language?",
    "answer": "It supports usual declaration of primitive data types",
    "option1": "It allows code to be written outside classes",
    "option2": "It does not support pointers",
    "option3": "It doesn’t support all types of inheritance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which among the following doesn’t come under OOP concept?",
    "answer": "Platform independent",
    "option1": "Data hiding",
    "option2": "Message passing",
    "option3": "Data binding"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the correct syntax of inheritance?",
    "answer": "class derived_classname : access base_classname{ /*define class body*/ };",
    "option1": "class base_classname :access derived_classname{ /*define class body*/ };",
    "option2": "class derived_classname : base_classname{ /*define class body*/ };",
    "option3": "class base_classname : derived_classname{ /*define class body*/ };"
  },
  {
    "question": "The feature by which one object can interact with another object is _____________",
    "answer": "Message Passing",
    "option1": "Message reading",
    "option2": "Data transfer",
    "option3": "Data Binding"
  },
  {
    "question": "In object-oriented programming, objects are instances of classes.",
    "answer": "True",
    "option1": "False",
    "option2": "TFNULL",
    "option3": "TFNULL"
  },
  {
    "question": "Encapsulation is a principle that combines data and methods into a single unit called an object.",
    "answer": "True",
    "option1": "False",
    "option2": "TFNULL",
    "option3": "TFNULL"
  },
  {
    "question": "Inheritance allows a class to inherit properties and methods from another class",
    "answer": "True",
    "option1": "False",
    "option2": "TFNULL",
    "option3": "TFNULL"
  },
  {
    "question": "Polymorphism refers to the ability of an object to take on many forms and respond differently based on the context. ",
    "answer": "True",
    "option1": "False",
    "option2": "TFNULL",
    "option3": "TFNULL"
  },
  {
    "question": "Abstraction is the process of hiding complex implementation details and exposing only essential features to the user. ",
    "answer": "True",
    "option1": "False",
    "option2": "TFNULL",
    "option3": "TFNULL"
  },
  {
    "question": "Object-oriented programming is limited to only a few programming languages and cannot be used in web development. ",
    "answer": "False",
    "option1": "True",
    "option2": "TFNULL",
    "option3": "TFNULL"
  },
  {
    "question": "In object-oriented programming, multiple inheritance allows a class to inherit from multiple classes.",
    "answer": "False",
    "option1": "True",
    "option2": "TFNULL",
    "option3": "TFNULL"
  },
  {
    "question": "Objects communicate with each other by sending messages and receiving responses.",
    "answer": "True",
    "option1": "False",
    "option2": "TFNULL",
    "option3": "TFNULL"
  },
  {
    "question": "Object-oriented programming promotes reusability of code through the concept of classes and objects",
    "answer": "True",
    "option1": "False",
    "option2": "TFNULL",
    "option3": "TFNULL"
  },
  {
    "question": "Object-oriented programming is a programming paradigm that focuses on the procedural execution of code. ",
    "answer": "False",
    "option1": "True",
    "option2": "TFNULL",
    "option3": "TFNULL"
  }

]